(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Departure!
Composition: 羽鳥風仁 • Lyrics: 羽鳥風仁 • TEAM HUNTER
Composition: Kazuhito Hatori • Lyrics: Kazuhito Hatori • TEAM HUNTER
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the earth
君は目覚めていく
You are waking up
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile
連れ出して！
Take me away!
孤独でも
Even if you're lonely
一人じゃないさ
You're not alone
生まれてきたことに
In the fact that you were born
必ず今がある
There is surely a "now"
優しさに
Overflowing with
満ちあふれてる
kindness
青い星に
To the blue planet
ありがとう
Thank you
You can smile again!
太陽浴びて
Basking in the sun
You can fly away!
世界は君の輝きを待ってる
The world is waiting for your radiance
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the earth
君は目覚めていく
You are waking up
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile
連れ出して！
Take me away!
You can smile!
始まりはいつでも遅くないさ
It's never too late for a beginning
何度でも立ち上がれ！
Rise up again and again!
最後まで
Until the end
諦めないさ
I won't give up
やり続けることに
In continuing to do so
必ず意味がある
there is surely meaning
You just try again!
闇を抜けて
Breaking through the darkness
You just go away!
未来はいつも僕たちを待ってる
The future is always waiting for us
大空駆け抜けて
Racing through the vast sky
海原越えて行け
Cross the wide ocean
天使の投げキッス
An angel's blown kiss
捕まえて！
Catch it!
You can try!
Departure!
…かった
…once
景色へ
to the scenery
飛び出そう
Let's fly out
明日！
Into tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the ground
君は目覚めていく
You're waking up
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile
連れ出して！
Take me away!
終わらない冒険に出かけよう
Let's set out on an endless adventure
いつまでも どこまでも
Forever and ever, no matter how far
流れ落ちる涙
The falling tears
勇気に変えていく
Will turn into courage
天使の羽広げ
Spreading angel wings
舞い上がれ！
Soar high!
悲しみも痛みも包み込んで
Embracing both sadness and pain
強くなれ
Become strong
明日！
Into tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて
Stepping firmly on the ground
君は目覚めていく
You're waking up
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile
連れ出して！
Take me away!
始まりはいつでも遅くないさ
It's never too late to start
何度でも！
Again and again!
立ち上がれ！
Rise up!
ファンサ
Fansa
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは愛の込もった投げキッスで
Repaying you with a loving blown kiss
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and please fall in love
やれること何でもします
I'll do anything I can
エンジーなしで体当たり挑戦
A head-on challenge with no pretense
捏造見つけたアンチコメ
Found fabricated anti-comments
ふざけんな 誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me, I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫 ここに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, everyone is here when I stand here
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは愛の込もった投げキッスで
Repaying you with a loving blown kiss
虜にする！もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでて愛の込もったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this loving special night
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you some fanservice!
お手紙も書いてください
Please write letters to me too
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and cherish them
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
It's too early for a scandal, but
裏切りません 宣言しときます
I'm declaring right now that I won't betray you
執拗い嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to persistent harassment
ふざけんな 強く生きてやる
Don't mess with me, I'll live strongly
だからやめない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
So I won't quit, the sore loser me is here
行くよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは愛の込もったムメイビームで
Repaying you with a loving Mumei Beam
大歓声！もっと！
A huge cheer! More!
まだまだね！
Not yet!
もっと！
More!
受け止めてね
Please accept it
愛のこもったわがままソング
A selfish song filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fanservice!
はぁ〜...
Haa~...
終わりが近づく寂しいな
The end is near, it's so lonely
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
I'm having fun but I feel like crying
次も、次も、また会えるよね
Next time, and the next, we'll meet again, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words overflowing with kindness,
心無い誰かの言葉さえも
and even the heartless words of some stranger,
必要なんだ　必要なんだ
I need them, I need them all
強くなろう
To become stronger
好きに叫んで　もっと！
Shout as you please, more!
堪能しちゃって　もっと！
Enjoy yourself to the fullest, more!
忘れないでね　特別な日になりますように
Don't forget this, may it become a special day
共に歌おう　ずっと！
Let's sing together, forever!
共に歩もう　ずっと！
Let's walk together, forever!
合言葉は　とびきりの...
Our password is a super...
L・O・V・E！
L-O-V-E!
好きになって　もっと！
Fall in love with me, more!
私を見て　もっと！
Look at me, more!
恩返しは　愛のこもった...
My way of returning the favor is with a...
...投げキッスで！
...blowing kiss filled with love!
虜にする　もっと！
I'll captivate you, more!
夢を見せる　もっと！
I'll show you a dream, more!
楽しんでって　愛のこもった...
Have fun, with a...
...スペシャルナイト！
...special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fanservice!
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Composition: 音羽-otoha- / Lyrics: ZAQ
Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet
Composition: otoha / Lyrics: ZAQ
突然降る夕立　あら　傘もないや　イヤイヤ
A sudden evening shower, oh, I don't even have an umbrella, no no
空のご機嫌なんか伺うの　やめな
Stop checking on the sky's mood
季節の変わり目の風は　今日は何を食やいいんだろう
The wind at the turn of the seasons, I wonder what I should eat today
春と秋どこ行っちゃったんだよ
Where did spring and autumn go?
息もできない　情報の圧力
I can't even breathe, the pressure of information
めまいの螺旋だ　私はどこにいる
A spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに　こんなに　息の音がするのに
Even though I can hear the sound of my breath so clearly
変だね　世界の音がしない
It's strange, I can't hear the world's sound
足りない　足りない　誰にも気づかれない
Not enough, not enough, noticed by no one
殴り書きみたいな音　出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed in a state where I couldn't make a sound like a scribble
ありのままなんて　誰に見せるんだ
Who am I supposed to show my true self to?
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ　ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Stupid me, I just sing, shall I spill it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業も　何となくなんだ
Even the task of restring with Elixir is just kind of whatever
欠けた爪を少し触る
I touch my chipped nail a bit
半径300mmの体で　必死に鳴いてる
With a body with a 300mm radius, I'm crying out desperately
音楽にとっちゃ　此処が地球だな
For music, this must be the Earth
空気を吸い込んで　空を殴るよ
I inhale the air and punch the sky
何にもできない　私は無力さ
I can't do anything, I'm powerless
だけどさ　その手で　この鉄を弾いたら
But you know, if I pluck these steel strings with those hands,
何かが変わって見えた
something seemed to change
眩しい　眩しい　そんなに光るなよ
Dazzling, dazzling, don't shine so brightly
私のダサさが　より濃くなってしまうだろう
It'll just make my uncoolness stand out even more
何でこんなに熱くなっちゃってんだ　止まらない
Why am I getting so fired up? I can't stop
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
うるさいんだって　心臓
Shut up already, my heart
蒼い惑星　ひとりぼっちがいっぱいの
A blue planet, full of lonely people
音を聞いてきた
I've been listening to the sounds
回り続けて　億年　一瞬でも
Continuing to spin for billions of years, even for an instant...
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet
Don't worry, it can loud!
聞いて　聴けよ
Listen, hear me
私は　私は　私はここにいる
I am, I am, I am here
殴り書きみたいな音　出せない状態で叫びたいんだよ
In a state where I can't let out sounds like scribbles, I want to scream
なんかになりたい　なりたい　何者かでいい
I want to become something, become something, anyone is fine
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Foolish me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
ハロ／ハワユ
Hello/How Are You
ハロ　窓を開けて　小さく呟いた
Hello, I opened the window and whispered softly
ハワユ　誰もいない　部屋で一人
How are you, alone in a room with no one
モーニン　朝が来たよ　土砂降りの朝が
Morning, morning has come, a morning of pouring rain
チクタク　私のネジを　誰か巻いて
Tick-tock, someone wind my spring
La la la...
ハロ　昔のアニメに　そんなのいたっけな
Hello, was there someone like that in an old anime?
ハワユ　羨ましいな　皆に愛されて
How are you, I'm jealous, being loved by everyone
スリーピン　馬鹿なこと言ってないで　支度しなくちゃ
Sleeping, stop talking nonsense, I have to get ready
クライン　涙の跡を隠すため
Crying, to hide the traces of my tears
もう口癖になった「まあいっか」
"Oh well" has already become my catchphrase
昨日の言葉がふと頭をよぎる
Yesterday's words suddenly cross my mind
「もう君には全然期待してないから」
"I'm not expecting anything from you anymore"
そりゃまあ私だって自分に期待なんてしてないけれど
Well, even I don't have any expectations for myself, but...
アレは一体どういうつもりですか
What on earth do you mean by that?
喉元まで出かかった言葉
Words that almost came out of my throat,
口を突いて出たのは嘘
but what came out of my mouth was a lie
こうして今日も私は貴重な
And so, today again, I...
言葉を食い潰して生きてゆく
continue to live while wasting precious words
何故隠してしまうのですか
Why do you end up hiding it?
嗤われるのが怖いのですか
Are you afraid of being laughed at?
誰にも会いたくないのですか
Do you not want to see anyone?
それ本当ですか
Is that really true?
曖昧という名の海に溺れて
Drowning in a sea called ambiguity,
息も出来ないほど苦しいの
it's so painful I can't even breathe
少し声が聞きたくなりました
I felt like hearing your voice a little
本当に弱いな
I'm really weak
一向に進まない支度の途中
In the middle of getting ready, making no progress,
朦朧とした頭で思う
I think with a hazy head
「理由をつけて休んでしまおうかな」
"Maybe I'll make an excuse and take the day off"
いやいや分かってますって
No, no, I know, I know
なんとなく言ってみただけだよ
I just said it for no reason
分かってるから怒らないでよ
I know, so don't get mad
幸せだろうと不幸せだろうと
Whether I'm happy or unhappy,
平等に残酷に朝日は昇る
the morning sun rises equally and cruelly
生きてくだけで精一杯の私
I'm doing my best just to live
これ以上何を望むというの
What more do you want from me?
何故気にしてしまうのですか
Why do you end up caring?
本当は愛されたいのですか
Do you actually want to be loved?
その手を離したのは誰ですか
Who was it that let go of that hand?
気が付いてますか
Have you realized?
人生にタイムカードがあるなら
If life has a time card,
終わりの時間はいつなんだろう
when would the clock-out time be?
私が生きた分の給料は
The salary for the time I lived,
誰が払うんですか
who pays for that?
Thank you
ありがとうって言いたいの
I want to say thank you
Thank you
ありがとうって言いたいよ
I want to say thank you
Thank you
一度だけでもいいから
Even if it's just once
心の底から大きな声で
With a loud voice from the bottom of my heart
ありがとうって言いたいの
I want to say thank you
何故隠してしまうのですか？
Why do you keep it hidden away?
本当は聞いてほしいのですか？
Do you actually want someone to listen?
絶対に笑ったりしないから
I'll never laugh at you
話してみませんか？
So won't you try and talk to me?
口を開かなければわからない
If you don't open your mouth, I'll never know
思ってるだけでは伝わらない
Just thinking it won't get through
なんて面倒くさい生き物でしょう
What a troublesome kind of creature
人間というのは
A human being is
ハロー ハワユ
Hello, how are you
あなたに
To you
ハロー ハワユ
Hello, how are you
you
Composition: dai / Lyrics: 癒月
Composition: dai / Lyrics: Yuzuki
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you and what are you doing now?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you somewhere under this continuous sky?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
The thing that had been filling my heart until now
失って初めて気づいた
I only realized after losing it
こんなに私を支えてくれていたこと
How much it had been supporting me
こんなに笑顔をくれていたこと
How many smiles it had been giving me
失ってしまった代償は
The price of losing it
とてつもなく大きすぎて
Is just far too great
取り戻そうと必死に手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
I reach out and struggle desperately
to take it back, but...
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
It slips through like the wind
届けそうで届かない
So close, yet so far
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
Loneliness and despair tighten my chest
心が壊れそうになるけれど
And my heart feels like it's about to break, but...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
Your smile that remains in my memories
私をいつも励ましてくれる
Always gives me encouragement
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once more
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, it will surely be okay
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always be laughing by each other's side
あなたのすぐそばで
Right by your side
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you and what are you doing now?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you somewhere under this continuous sky?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか？
Are you smiling like you always do?
今はただそれを願い続ける
Now I just continue to wish for that
もうあなたから愛されることも
Even the fact that I'll no longer be loved by you...
必要とされることもない
...or be needed by you anymore.
そして私は
And so, I am...
こうして一人ぼっちで
...here, all alone.
あの時あなたは何て言ったの?
What did you say back then?
届かない言葉は宙を舞う
Unreachable words dance in the air.
わかってるのに今日もしてしまう
Even though I know, I end up doing it again today.
叶わぬ願いごとを
Making a wish that won't come true.
離さないで ぎゅっと 手を握っていて
Don't let go, hold my hand tightly.
あなたと二人 ずっといて
Stay with me forever, just the two of us.
繋いだその手は温かくて
The hand I held was so warm...
優しかった
...and kind.
あなたはいつもそうやって私を
You always used to tease me like that...
怒らせて最後は泣かすんだ
...and make me cry in the end.
だけど後になってごめんねと言う
But then you'd come later and say "sorry."
その顔 好きだった
I loved that face of yours.
離さないで ぎゅっと そう思い切り
Don't let go, hold me tight with all your might.
あなたの腕の中にいたい
I want to be in your arms.
二人でおでこを合わせながら
While we touch our foreheads together...
眠るの
...we fall asleep.
もう二度と会えないってことを
The fact that we'll never meet again...
知ってたの?
...did you know it?
離さないで ぎゅっと あなたが好き
Don't let go, hold me tight, I love you.
もう一度だって笑ってくれないの?
Won't you smile for me just once more?
あなたの温もりが消えちゃう前に
Before your warmth disappears...
抱きしめて
...hold me.
忘れてしまった
I have forgotten...
ことも 言葉 時を求めている
...those things, seeking words and time.
...巡り合った 無名の先で 君と出会った
...the unknown beyond where we turned, I met you.
名前も 顔も わからない君なんだか 懐かしいような気がした
You, whose name and face I don't know, somehow felt nostalgic.
世界に穴を埋めてゆくように ふざけ合って 笑い合って
As if filling the holes in the world, joking and laughing together.
世界 ああああ あのどこかにいる君のため
World, ahhh, for you who are somewhere out there.
今 ああああ 生きているよ 僕ら
Now, ahhh, we are living.
無名のまま
Still nameless.
例えばこれが 映し出された幻でも
Even if this is an image projected as an illusion.
確かに感じる 今君がそこにいること
I certainly feel that you are there now.
名前も 顔も わからない君さよなら してしまえば終わりだ
You, whose name and face I don't know, if I say goodbye, it's over.
君がいなきゃ穴は大きくなる 構わないさ すべて作る
Without you, the hole gets bigger. I don't mind, I'll make it all.
世界 ああああ あのどこかにいる君はどこ
World, ahhh, where are you, who are somewhere out there?
今 ああああ ここにいるよ 私
Now, ahhh, I am here.
無名
Nameless.
あたり一面真っ暗な世界 真っ逆さまに落ちてゆく
A world dark all around, falling headlong.
無名だからこの世界には 忘れられて消えちゃうの
Because I'm nameless, I'll be forgotten and disappear from this world.
それでも君が求めるのなら この胸にあいた穴に今
But if you still seek me, into this hole in my heart now...
君から私へと風が通り抜け 記憶の振りが今君の元へと行く
A wind passes from you to me, and a wave of memories goes to you now.
世界 ああああ あのどこかにいる君のため
World, ahhh, for you who are somewhere out there.
今 ああああ 生きているよ 私
Now, ahhh, I am living.
無名のまま
Still nameless.
Oh hi hoomans! / Hoomansのみなさん、
Oh hi hoomans! / Everyone, Hoomans,
Thank you so much for the last three and a half years. / この3年半、最後まで支えてくれて本当にありがとうね。
Thank you so much for the last three and a half years. / Thank you for supporting me until the end during these three and a half years.
Even in writing, I know I won't be able to fully convey my feelings. / 文章ではきっと、私の気持ちをすべて伝えきれないと思いますが、
Even in writing, I know I won't be able to fully convey my feelings. / I'm sure I won't be able to fully express all my feelings in writing, but...
本当にみなさんのおかげで、私の人生がとても豊かなものになりました。
You have truly changed my life for the better.
ここから離れていっても、どんなことがあっても、みなさんのことを想っています。
Wherever I go, no matter what I face, I will remember you!
みなさんがくれた優しさと支えは、これからもずっと私の心の中にあります。
I will always carry the kindness and support you showed me in my heart.
おかげさまで、想像以上のことがたくさんできました。
I was able to do more than I ever imagined because of you.
この気持ちは、一生忘れません。
I will never forget this feeling!
私がhololiveにいたことが、誰かにとって少しでも力になれたなら、
I hope that my presence in hololive was a good one.
誰かに笑顔を届けられたなら、生きていてよかったと心から思います。
Any moment of joy I might have brought someone makes me even happier to be alive!
それは私にとって、かけがえのない宝物です。
It is a priceless treasure to me.
一緒に過ごしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for being here with me.
思いきりありのままの自分で楽しくいられるあたたかい場所もくれてありがとう。
Thank you for giving me a warm space to be silly and have fun.
そしてNanashi Mumeiでいさせてくれて、本当にありがとう。
And thank you for letting me be Nanashi Mumei.
Mumei